Kanaksinh Dodiya Full Stack In Android

Profile

Expert in Enterprise as Android Trainer and Mobile application development 9+ years. Skilled at Manage Course Content, Handling projects, leading teams, mentoring team members, developing architecture, design, and requirements. Demonstrated ability to understand and improve legacy code and to become proficient at new technologies quickly.

Experience

- 1. Android App Consultant at KarmDude
- Android Technical Consultant & Project Coordinator,
 Versatile Techno Pvt Ltd , Ahmedabad, India Mar 2016 to till Date
- 3. Sr. Developer, Agile Infoways pvt Ltd, Ahmedabad, India Sep 2014 to Mar 2016
- 4. Developer, IndiaNIC Infotech Ltd, Ahmedabad, India Aug 2011 to Sep 2014
 I have conceptualized, designed, developed and deployed various types of applications for android based mobile phones. I have created handset specific user interface (UI) for mobile phones and tablets and also researched application acceptance and solicited feedback from users to make the new and existing applications more user friendly.

Education

B.E (Computer Engineering), Gujarat University, Gujarat, India, 2011

Skills

Programming Language: Basic core Java, XML, DOM, SAX Parsers, HTML/CSS, SQLite, JSON.

Project Management Tools: Zoho, Basecamps, Company ERP, Asana

Android Technologies & Manage Project : Android, iOS, PHP

Database: SQLite.

Operating System: Windows, Linux, Mac

Testing and Integration Tools: Subversion (SVN), Robotm(Android)

Development Tools: Eclipse, Android Studio

Summary of work done at Versatile Techno, Agile Infoways & IndiaNIC As Project Coordinator and Trainer,

Managed multiple small to medium-sized web-based software development projects to successful implementation.

List of application and website.

Privilege App, Health on Demand, OnHi, Wheel, Procabby, Ruffle Rush, Team finder, Buzz Me, Eroute waterless car wash App.

Velfie (Video Selfie App)

Make Fun using this app it's nothing but video selfie app, using this app you can share your video with different voice.

Technologies used with the project

Android 4.0+, FFmpeg Integration, Custom camera integration, Restfully integration and social media app integration

Role: Developer

Play Store URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.velfie

Lease Locator:

It is simple Oilfield lease locator app, Easy to use - shows you the map right as you enter a location. Remembers every search in history, so you can quickly find past locations.

Technologies used with the project

Android 4+, Map integration, Custom wheel Library, In App Purchase Subscription implementation.

Role: Developer

Play Store URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.terraform.lsdlocate&hl=en

DLD App (Dubai land department application)

Project Brief

Dubai land department app is totally base on Dubai government service, news and e service of land department, provide some base calculator like service cal, mortgage, rental etc. This application is also provide the list of developer which work on the department and also some broker list to the part of the department.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.2 to Android 4.4, SQLite Database, Soap parsing, Fragments

Role: Developer

Play Store URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ae.gov.dubailand.app

Top Chef Restaurant / Emmy Restaurant

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.3+, SQLite Database, use Javascript, and Html concept.

Role: Developer

Key Challenges and Results

To integrate the Native android and javascript with html use java interfaces.

Play Store URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.emmy.app

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ng.com.topchef

Mobile Cash App (Rs. 300+ Free Mobile Recharge)

Project Brief

Mobile Cash is a mobile app that gives you Mobile Cash on all your online shopping, and for all the shopping your friends do as well! It's super awesome to see money pour in, especially when your friends use the Mobile Cash App and you get money too.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.3 and above OS Support, Google Referrer police integration, Google Analytics, etc

Role: Developer

DMC ER Now

Project Brief

This is the Official Detroit Medical Center Emergency Room Wait Times, Directions and Healthcare Toolkit. With DMC ER Now, Track and store personal medical data for you and your loved ones, Prepare for emergencies with our Emergency Medical Guide, Get easy automated directions to Detroit Medical Center hospitals.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.3, SQLite Database, google Map

Role: Developer

Key Challenges and Results

Deal with the Google map and Database.

Play Store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sunnymediagroup.dmcernow&hl=en

Mr. Ticket Traffic Attorney

Project Brief

Find DUI checkpoints or local crime by list. click on DUI icon and make sure to click on "News or Press Release". Find already existing Camera Locations by list. Find local Police Stations by list. Find Sheriff Stations by list. Find Weigh/Scale stations by list. Find Local CHP offices by list Map functions include: Update/Add DUI Checkpoints, Red Light Camera Locations & Speed Traps App alerts you when 1 mile away from any checkpoint, camera ticket or speed trap.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.3 and Up, SQLite Database, Map V2, Json Parsing. Role: Developer

Key Challenges and Results

Deal with Map V2.

Play Store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mrticket&hl=en

Madhya Pradesh / Delhi / Punjab Tourism

Project Brief

The application houses the information about the state on the homepage. You can choose a city and then you can browse the sightseeing places. The app also provides accurate information about how to get to your chosen destination from your current position.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.2+, SQLite Database, Parse.comRole: Development, design, implementation

Key Challenges and Results : Parse.com

Play store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.indianic.madhyapradeshtourism&hl=en https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.indianic.delhitourism&hl=en https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.indianic.punjabtourism&hl=en

BHealthy Baby

Project Brief

Are you expecting? Expect the best with BHealthy Baby, the baby app from Baptist Health System. BHealthy Baby

is for moms to be who are on the go and want to be well prepared for every stage of pregnancy. From health tips to tracking tools, BHealthy Baby is here to help you and your baby have a happy and healthy experience.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.2+, SQLite Database

Role: Development, design, implementation Key Challenges and Results: Database Design

PlayStore URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sunnymediagroup.baptist

RGV Baby

Project Brief

RGV Baby is for moms to be who are on the go and want to be well prepared for every stage of pregnancy. From health tips to tracking tools, RGV Baby is here to help you and your baby have a happy and healthy experience.

You can change the language to Spanish inside the app!

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.2+, SQLite Database

Role: Development, design, implementation Key Challenges and Results: Database Design

PlayStore URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sunnymediagroup.rgvbaby

The Summit Radio

Project Brief

The Summit with you! With The Summit Radio app, not only can you listen to The Summit, you can also

listen to all of HD channels. With The Summit Radio app, you can stream any of our four "stations" get

artist and title information . Request a song share with your friends on Facebook and Twitter, or by email

from your phone. Find help/treatment with just a touch (Rock and Recovery).

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.2+, Radio streaming.

Role: Development, design, implementation Key Challenges and Results: Radio Streaming

PlayStore URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.thesummit.waps&;hl=en

The DMC Mobile Maternity

Project Brief

Mobile Maternity is for moms to be who are on the go and want to be well prepared for every stage of pregnancy. From health tips to tracking tools, Mobile Maternity is here to help you and your baby have a happy and healthy experience.

Technologies used within the project

Android 2.2+, Radio streaming.

Role: Development, design, implementation

PlayStore URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sunnymediagroup.dmcbaby

Contact Info

Email: mkarmdude@gmail.com

Phone: 09601879846 Pan no: BETPD5663J